Guide to the Time Inc. Harry Harding Files on Corporate Identity 1967-1971 MS 3009-RG 42
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Harry Harding Files on Corporate Identity
1967-1971
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 42
1.1 Linear feet in 1 record carton, 1 flat box
Corporate executive Harry Harding's files document his work on Time Inc.'s corporate identity, specifically attempting to create a new corporate logo or trademark for use throughout the company.
Biographical Note
Time Inc. hired advertising executive Harry Harding in 1963 in a new corporate executive position reporting to president James Linen. According to his obituary in the New York Times, Harding worked on the development of international editions of magazines.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers. Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Related Archival Materials Note
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Scope and Contents Note
Harry Harding's files document his work on Time Inc.'s corporate identity, specifically attempting to create a new corporate logo or trademark for use throughout the company. A 1968 memoranda to James Linen titled "The Need for a World-Wide Identity Program" lists the variety of marks used by Time Inc. and its subsidiaries and describes his proposed project to create a cohesive corporate identity for the company. Files include samples of proposed logo designs on letterhead, envelopes, business cards and the corporate jet; correspondence and memoranda discussing the need for corporate design, design requirements, and trademarks of other companies; and a collection of other companies annual reports and other materials. Notes found with the loose material indicate these are Harding's materials and some materials were sent by Louis Slovinsky, possibly meaning that Harding worked with the corporate publicity office on this project.
Arrangement Note
Organized alphabetically with arrangement imposed.
Corporate image; Organization files; Corporation records; Corporations -- History; Harding, Harry; Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History
- General, 1967-1968; 222831 (Offsite-box 1787, Folder 1)
- Corporate Mark, 1967-1969; 222832 (Offsite-box 1787, Folder 2-3)
- Designs, approximately 1968; 222833 (Offsite-box 1787, Folder 4)
- Eastex Style Manual, undated; 222834 (Offsite-box 1787, Folder 5)
- Examples from Other Companies, 1967-1969; 222835 (Offsite-box 1787, Folder 6-7)
- Mock-ups, approximately 1968; 222836 (Offsite-box 1787, Folder 8)
- Notes Identifying Owner of Records, undated; 222837 (Offsite-box 1787, Folder 9)
- Project "S", 1970; 222838 (Offsite-box 1787, Folder 10)
- Samples, approximately 1968; 222839 (Offsite-box 1787, Folder 11-13)
- Samples, approximately 1968; 222841 (Offsite-box 1788)
- Time-Life Logo, 1968-1971; 222840 (Offsite-box 1787, Folder 14)